PROFESSOR: Here's a case where your
graph doesn't have to be broken into
pieces, but it's still
simple in some way.
And this is in a very important case
that we'll see coming up over and over
again in this class, and that's the
case where your constraint graph--
it's not separated into pieces, but
it's not a general graph, either.
The intermediate ground that
it's tree structured.
So here's a case of a constraint graph
which has tree structure, which means
no loops-- no cycles in
the constraint graph.
So there's a theorem--
and we'll see why this is true-- that
says that if the constraint graph has
no loops, then the CSP can be solved in
time that is linear in the size of
the graph, and quadratic in
the size of the domains.
That's so much better than general
CSPs where it's exponential.
Right.
So tree structured is much, much more
efficient, and it's not crazy that you
would find something either tree
structured or nearly tree structured.
This is a particular case where there's
a connection between the kind
of syntactic restrictions, the structure
of the problem, what we're
allowed to stay in the CSP, right--
here, the restriction is that it be
tree structured--
and the complexity of reasoning that
results from that restriction.